Guide to the Wells Fargo Steinbeck Collection, 1892-1981
Department of Special Collections
- Series 5. John Steinbeck Letters to Carolee Rodgers, 1926-1962
  - [John Steinbeck], New York, to Carolee Rodgers, Berkeley, CA Thursday [1950 Mar. 30] (Box 6, Folder 72)
    - ALS, 2 pp. (1 leaf) + envelope
  - [John Steinbeck], n.p. [New York], to Carolee [Rodgers], n.p. [1950] Apr. 7 (Box 6, Folder 73)
    - ALS, 4 pp. (2 leaves)
  - [John Steinbeck], New York, to Carolee Rodgers, Berkeley, CA 1950 Apr. 22 (Box 6, Folder 74)
    - ALS, 1 p. + envelope
  - [John Steinbeck], New York, to Carolee Rodgers, Berkeley, CA [1950] July 24 (Box 6, Folder 75)
    - ALS, 2 pp. (1 leaf) + envelope
  - [John Steinbeck], n.p. [New York], to Carolee [Rodgers], n.p. [1950] Oct. 31 (Box 6, Folder 76)
    - ALS, 2 pp. (1 leaf)
  - [John Steinbeck], n.p. [New York], to Carolee [Rodgers], n.p. [1950] Nov. 6 (Box 6, Folder 77)
    - ALS, 3 pp. (2 leaves)
  - [John Steinbeck], n.p. [New York], to [Carolee Rodgers], n.p. n.d. [1950 Nov.] (Box 6, Folder 78)
    - ALS, 2 pp. (1 leaf)
  - [John Steinbeck], New York, to Carolee Rodgers, Berkeley, CA [1950] Nov. 17 (Box 6, Folder 79)
    - ALS, 2 pp. (1 leaf)
  - [John Steinbeck], n.p. [New York], to Carolee [Rodgers], n.p. Monday [1950 Nov. 27?] (Box 6, Folder 80)
    - ALS, 4 pp. (2 leaves)
  - [John Steinbeck], New York, to Carolee Rodgers, Berkeley, CA 1950 Dec. 4 (Box 6, Folder 81)
    - ALS, 1 p. + envelope
  - [John Steinbeck], New York, to Carolee Rodgers, New York 1950 Dec. 29 (Box 4, Folder 55)
    - APCS
  - [John Steinbeck], New York, to Carolee Rodgers, Berkeley, CA 1951 Jan. 30 (Box 6, Folder 82)
    - ALS, 1 p. + envelope
  - John Steinbeck, New York, to Carolee Rodgers, Berkeley, CA 1951 Mar. 1 (Box 4, Folder 56)
    - APCS
  - John Steinbeck, Sag Harbor, to Bob and Carolee Finney, Berkeley, CA 1962 Oct. 30 (Box 4, Folder 57)
    - APCS
- Series 6. Elaine Steinbeck Letters, 1951-1969
  - Elaine Steinbeck, Bermuda, to Mrs. C. J. [Esther] Rodgers, Watsonville, CA 1951 Jan. 2 (Box 4, Folder 58)
    - APCS
  - Elaine Steinbeck, Sag Harbor, to Esther and Carrol Rodgers, Watsonville, CA 1959 Jan. 9 (Box 4, Folder 59)
    - ALS, 3 pp. (2 leaves) + envelope
  - Elaine Steinbeck, London, to Esther Rodgers, Watsonville, CA 1961 Sept. 17 (Box 4, Folder 60)
    - ALS, 1 p. + envelope
  - [Elaine Steinbeck], Rome, to Esther Rodgers, Watsonville, CA [1961] Dec. 20 (Box 4, Folder 61)
    - APCS
  - Elaine Steinbeck, Positano, Italia, to E[sther Rodgers], Watsonville, CA 1962 Apr. 11 (Box 4, Folder 62)
    - ALS, 1 p.
  - [Elaine Steinbeck], n.p. [Vienna], to "Dear Ones," n.p. [1963] Dec. 2 (Box 4, Folder 63)
    - TL (carbon), 17 pp. (10 leaves)
  - Elaine Steinbeck, New York, to Mrs. C.J. [Esther] Rodgers, Watsonville, CA 1963 Mar. 12 (Box 4, Folder 64)
    - APCS
  - [Elaine Steinbeck], Sag Harbor, to "E and M" [Esther Rodgers and Mary Dekker], Watsonville, CA 1963 Aug. 14 (Box 4, Folder 65)
    - APCS
  - [Elaine Steinbeck], Vatican City, to Mrs. C. J. [Esther] Rodgers, Watsonville, CA Saturday [1964 Mar. 28?] (Box 4, Folder 66)
    - APCS
  - [Elaine Steinbeck], Falmouth, MA, Esther [Rodgers], n.p. [Watsonville, CA] n.d. [1965 May 31] (Box 4, Folder 67)
    - ANS
  - [Elaine Steinbeck], Cork, Ireland, to Esther Rodgers, Watsonville, CA 1966 Jan. 11 (Box 4, Folder 68)
    - ALS, 4 pp. (2 leaves) + envelope
  - [Elaine Steinbeck], Haifa, Israel, to B. and E. [Beth Ainsworth and Esther Rodgers], n.p. [1966] Feb. 19 (Box 4, Folder 69)
    - ALS, 4 pp.
  - [Elaine Steinbeck], Waikiki Beach, [Honolulu], HI, to E. and B. [Esther Rodgers and Beth Ainsworth], n.p. Tuesday [1966 Dec. 6] (Box 4, Folder 70)
    - ALS, 2 pp. (1 leaf)
  - [Elaine Steinbeck], Saigon, to E. and B. [Esther Rodgers and Beth Ainsworth], n.p. [1966] Dec. 20 (Box 4, Folder 71)
    - ALS, 2 pp.
  - [Elaine Steinbeck], Saigon, to E. and B. [Esther Rodgers and Beth Ainsworth], Watsonville, CA [1967] Jan. 6 (Box 4, Folder 72)
    - ALS, 2 pp. (1 leaf) + envelope
  - [Elaine Steinbeck], Saigon, to "Dear Ones," n.p. [1967] Jan. 15 (Box 4, Folder 73)
    - ALS, 2 pp. (1 leaf)
  - [Elaine Steinbeck], Bangkok, to Esther [Rodgers] and Beth [Ainsworth], n.p. [1967] Jan. 29 (Box 4, Folder 74)
    - ALS, 2 pp.
  - [Elaine Steinbeck], Bangkok, to B. and E. [Beth Ainsworth and Esther Rodgers], Watsonville, CA [1967] Feb. 10 (Box 4, Folder 75)
    - ALS, 2 pp. + envelope
  - [Elaine Steinbeck], Penang, Malaysia, to B. and E. [Beth Ainsworth and Esther Rodgers], n.p. [1967] Feb. 25 (Box 4, Folder 76)
    - ALS, 2 pp. (1 leaf)
  - [Elaine Steinbeck], Jakarta, to Mrs. C. J. [Esther] Rodgers, Watsonville, CA [1967] Mar. 19 (Box 4, Folder 77)
    - APCS
  - [Elaine Steinbeck], Hong Kong, to "Dear Sisters," Watsonville, CA [1967] Mar. 31 (Box 4, Folder 78)
    - ALS, 2 pp. + envelope
  - Elaine Steinbeck, New York, to E. and B. [Esther Rodgers and Beth Ainsworth], Watsonville, CA 1967 June 3 (Box 4, Folder 79)
    - APCS
  - Elaine Steinbeck, Sag Harbor, to E[sther Rodgers], n.p. [Watsonville, CA] 1967 Aug. 23 (Box 4, Folder 80)
    - ALS, 2 pp. (1 leaf)
  - [Elaine Steinbeck], New York, to E. and B. [Esther Rodgers and Beth Ainsworth], n.p. n.d. [1967 Oct.] (Box 6, Folder 83)
    - ALS, 1p.
  - Elaine Steinbeck, New York, to [Esther Rodgers], n.p. [Watsonville, CA] n.d. [1967 Oct. ] (Box 4, Folder 81)
    - APC
  - Elaine Steinbeck, n.p. [New York], to E. [Esther Rodgers], n.p. [Watsonville, CA] n.d. [1967 Oct.] (Box 4, Folder 82)
    - ALS, 4 pp. (2 leaves)
  - Elaine Steinbeck, New York, to E. [Esther Rodgers], n.p. [Watsonville, CA] n.d. [1967 Fall] (Box 4, Folder 83)
    - ALS, 4 pp. (2 leaves)
  - [Elaine Steinbeck], n.p. [New York], to E. and B. [Esther Rodgers and Beth Ainsworth], n.p. n.d. [1967 Dec.] (Box 4, Folder 84)
    - ALS, 4 pp. (2 leaves)
  - Elaine Steinbeck, New York, to E. [Esther Rodgers], n.p. [Watsonville, CA] 1968 Mar. 8 (Box 4, Folder 85)
    - ALS, 2 pp. (1 leaf)
  - [Elaine Steinbeck], Sag Harbor, to E. [Esther Rodgers], n.p. [Watsonville, CA] 1968 July 2 (Box 4, Folder 86)
    - ALS, 2 pp. (1 leaf) + envelope
  - Elaine Steinbeck, Sag Harbor, to E. [Esther Rodgers], n.p. [Watsonville, CA] 1968 Aug. 29 (Box 4, Folder 87)
    - APCS
  - [Elaine Steinbeck], Sag Harbor, to E. [Esther Rodgers], n.p. [Watsonville, CA] 1968 Sept. 25 (Box 4, Folder 88)
    - ALS, 2 pp. (1 leaf) + envelope
  - Elaine Steinbeck, Sag Harbor, to E. [Esther Rodgers], n.p. [Watsonville, CA] 1968 Oct. 4 (Box 4, Folder 89)
    - ALS, 4 pp. (2 leaves) + envelope
  - Elaine Steinbeck, Sag Harbor, to E. [Esther Rodgers], n.p. [Watsonville, CA] Saturday [1968 Oct. 19] (Box 4, Folder 90)
    - ALS, 4 pp. (2 leaves) + envelope
  - Elaine Steinbeck, Sag Harbor, to E. [Esther Rodgers], n.p. [Watsonville, CA] Wednesday [1968 Nov. 6] (Box 4, Folder 91)
    - APCS
  - [Elaine Steinbeck], n.p. [New York], to E. [Esther Rodgers], n.p. [Watsonville, CA] n.d. [1968 Nov. - Dec.] (Box 4, Folder 92)
    - ALS, 2 pp. (1 leaf)
  - Elaine Steinbeck, Sag Harbor, to E. [Esther Rodgers], n.p. [Watsonville, CA] n.d. [1968 Nov. - Dec.] (Box 4, Folder 93)
    - ALS, 6 pp. (3 leaves)
  - [Elaine Steinbeck], New York, to Carolee Finney, Kensington, CA 1969 Feb. 9 (Box 4, Folder 94)
    - ALS, 2 pp. (1 leaf) + envelope
  - Elaine Steinbeck, n.p., to E. [Esther Rodgers], n.p. [Watsonville, CA] n.d. [1969] (Box 6, Folder 84)
    - ALS, 2 pp. (1 leaf)
- Series 7. D.P. Trask Letters to Esther and Beth Steinbeck, 1907-1910
  - D. P. Trask, Paso Robles, CA, to Ester and Bess [Esther and Beth Steinbeck], n.p. [Salinas, CA] 1907 Feb. 10 (Box 4, Folder 95)
    - ALS, 1 p.
  - D. P. Trask, Paso Robles, CA, to Ester and Bess [Esther and Beth Steinbeck], n.p. [Salinas, CA] 1908 Feb. 9 (Box 4, Folder 96)
    - ALS, 1 p. + envelope
  - D. P. Trask, Paso Robles, CA, to Ester and Bess [Esther and Beth Steinbeck], n.p. [Salinas, CA] 1908 May 10 (Box 4, Folder 97)
    - ALS, 1 p.
  - D. P. Trask, Paso Robles, CA, to Ester and Bess [Esther and Beth Steinbeck], n.p. [Salinas, CA] 1908 May 17 (Box 4, Folder 98)
    - ALS, 1 p.
  - D. P. Trask, Paso Robles, CA, to Ester and Bess [Esther and Beth Steinbeck], n.p. [Salinas, CA] 1909 Dec. 19 (Box 4, Folder 99)
    - ALS, 1 p.
  - D. P. Trask, Paso Robles, CA, to Ester [Esther Steinbeck], n.p. [Salinas, CA] 1910 Dec. 18 (Box 4, Folder 100)
    - ALS, 1 p.
- Series 8. Nelson Valjean Letters to Esther Steinbeck Rodgers, 1969-1970
  - Nelson Valjean, Mill Valley, CA, to Mrs. [Esther] Rodgers, Watsonville, CA 1969 Nov. 4 (Box 4, Folder 101)
    - TLS, 2 pp.
  - Nelson Valjean, Mill Valley, CA, to Mrs. [Esther] Rodgers, n.p. [Watsonville, CA] 1969 Nov. 11 (Box 4, Folder 102)
    - TLS, 1 p.
  - Nelson Valjean, Mill Valley, CA, to Mrs. [Esther] Rodgers, n.p. [Watsonville, CA] 1969 Nov. 20 (Box 4, Folder 103)
    - TLS, 1 p. + envelope
  - Nelson Valjean, Mill Valley, CA, to Mrs. [Esther] Rodgers, n.p. [Watsonville, CA] 1970 Jan. 4 (Box 4, Folder 104)
    - TLS, 1 p.
  - [Esther Rodgers], n.p. [Watsonville, CA] to Nelson Valjean, n.p. [Mill Valley, CA] n.d. (Box 4, Folder 105)
    - AL, 1 p.
  - Nelson Valjean obituaries 1975 Oct. (Box 4, Folder 106)
- Series 9. John Steinbeck Poems and Short Stories
  - "Ah! any gift that I could bring" [poem] n.d. (Box 4, Folder 107)
    - TMS, 1 p.
  - "Oh! Heav'nly Muse, whose haughty dignity" [poem] n.d. (Box 4, Folder 108)
    - TMS, 1 p. [3 copies] + AN
  - Five poems, one note, one story for Christmas n.d. (Box 4, Folder 109)
    - AMs, 7 pp.
  - "The Kittens and the Curtain." [Short story] n.d. (Box 4, Folder 110)
    - TMs (with holographic corrections), 9 pp.
  - "Salad." [poem] 10 lines, typed. n.d. (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - TMs, 1 p.
  - "He's such a nice boy too" [poem] n.d. (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - TMs, 1 p.
  - Untitled: "Mrs. Steinbeck will render her" [poem] n.d. (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - TMs, 1 p.
  - "The Mild Beverage" [poem] n.d. (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - TMs, 1 p.
  - "Dirge of Success." [poem] n.d. (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - TMs (with holographic corrections), 1 p.
  - "Surround me with beautiful things" [poem] n.d. (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - TMs, 1 p.
  - The Chafed Rope [story] n.d. (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - TMs (fragment), 1 p.
  - Page 10 of a short story, Untitled. n.d. (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - TMs, 1 p.
  - The Affair at 1 Avenue de M... [story] n.d. (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - TMs, 9 pp. with TNS from Marlène Gray
- Series 10. Supplement, 1899-1979
  - Samuel and Elizabeth Hamilton's Golden Wedding Anniversary keepsake 1899 (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - 1 art original: watercolor; 13 x 8 cm.
  - John Adolf and Almira Ann Steinbeck's Golden Wedding Anniversary keepsake 1906 (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - 1 art original: watercolor; 13 x 8 cm.
  - Steinbeck family tree: key to Steinbeck Golden Wedding anniversary photograph. n.d. (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - John Adolph Steinbeck. "In June in the month of roses" [poem] n.d. (Box 6, Folder 85)
    - AMs (facsim.), 2 pp.
  - Olive Hamilton Steinbeck. "An Autograph" [poem] n.d. (Box 5, Folder 13)
    - AMs, 1 p.
  - Mahlon Blaine. Photograph of sketch of John Steinbeck n.d. (Box 5, Folder 14)
    - photomechanical reproduction, 14 x 24 cm.
  - John Ernst Steinbeck campaign card 1926 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Pascal Covici, New York, to Mrs. C.J. [Esther] Rodgers, Watsonville, CA 1957 May 8 (Box 5, Folder 16)
    - TLS, 1 p. + envelope
  - 29th International PEN Congress printed cards: John Steinbeck and John Dos Passos, including ANS from Dos Passos to "Steinbeck-san" 1957 (Box 5, Folder 17)
    - 2 printed cards
  - Esther Dayman Strong, Conakry, Republic of Guinea, to John Steinbeck, n.p. 1960 Jan. 29 (Box 5, Folder 18)
    - ALS, 2 pp.
  - Steinbeck, John, 1902-1968. Speech accepting the Nobel prize for literature, Stockholm, December 10, 1962. New York: Viking Press, [1962 or 1963]. 10, [2] p.: port.; 23 cm. 1963 (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Jacob K. Javits, New York, to Mrs. C.J. [Esther] Rodgers, Watsonville, CA. 1968 Dec. 31 (Box 5, Folder 20)
    - telegram
  - Esther Rodgers, Watsonville, CA, to The Hon. Senator Jacob K. Javits, Washington, DC n.d. [ca. 1969 Jan.] (Box 5, Folder 21)
    - ALS, 1 p.
  - Elaine Steinbeck, New York, to Esther [Rodgers], n.p. [Watsonville, CA; John Steinbeck chronology n.d. (Box 5, Folder 22)
    - ALS, 2 pp. (1 leaf) + TMs (facsim.), 15 pp.
  - Sketch of John Steinbeck for Steinbeck Library, Salinas; AN, [Beth Ainsworth], n.p. to [Esther Rodgers], n.p. n.d. (Box 5, Folder 23)
    - 1 photomechanical reproduction, 6 x 8 cm.; AN, 1 p.
  - Anne-Marie Schmitz. In Steinbeck Country. n.p.: Archive Press Production 1979 Jan. (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - Collection of 15¢ John Steinbeck commemorative U.S. Postage Stamps 1979 [Feb. 27] (Box 5, Folder 25)
    - 135 postage stamps
  - John Steinbeck commemorative U.S. Postage Stamps: first day of issue envelopes, Salinas, CA 1979 Feb. 27 (Box 5, Folder 26)
    - 6 stamped envelopes
  - John Steinbeck commemorative U.S. Postage Stamps: correspondence 1979 (Box 5, Folder 27)
  - John Steinbeck commemorative U.S. Postage Stamps: newspaper clippings 1979 Feb. 28 (Box 5, Folder 28)
  - John Steinbeck commemorative U.S. Postage Stamps: stamp album folder 1979 Feb. 27 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Clippings tipped-in to The Acts of King Arthur and his Noble Knights n.d. (Box 5, Folder 29)
  - Clippings tipped-in to America and Americans n.d. (Box 5, Folder 30)
  - Clippings tipped-in to Cannery Row n.d. (Box 5, Folder 31)
  - Clippings tipped-in to East of Eden n.d. (Box 5, Folder 32)
  - Clippings tipped-in to The Grapes of Wrath n.d. (Box 5, Folder 33)
  - Clippings tipped-in to Journal of a Novel n.d. (Box 5, Folder 34)
  - Clippings tipped-in to The Long Valley n.d. (Box 5, Folder 35)
  - Clippings tipped-in to The Moon is Down [includes John Steinbeck. "Reflections on a lunar eclipse," San Francisco Examiner (1963 Oct. 6)] n.d. (Box 5, Folder 36)
  - Clippings tipped-in to Of Mice and Men n.d. (Box 5, Folder 37)
  - Clippings tipped-in to The Pastures of Heaven n.d. (Box 5, Folder 38)
  - Clippings tipped-in to The Pearl n.d. (Box 5, Folder 39)
  - Clippings tipped-in to A Russian Journal n.d. (Box 5, Folder 40)
  - Clippings tipped-in to Steinbeck: a life in letters n.d. (Box 5, Folder 41)
  - Clippings tipped-in to Sweet Thursday n.d. (Box 5, Folder 42)
  - Clippings tipped-in to To a God Unknown n.d. (Box 5, Folder 43)
  - Clippings tipped-in to Tortilla Flat n.d. (Box 5, Folder 44)
  - Clippings tipped-in to Travels with Charley [includes facsim. of Steinbeck's Nobel address, 1962 Dec. 10] n.d. (Box 5, Folder 45)
  - Clippings tipped-in to Fontenrose, Joseph Eddy, John Steinbeck: an introduction n.d. (Box 5, Folder 46)
  - Clippings tipped-in to Moore, Harry Thornton. The novels of John Steinbeck n.d. (Box 5, Folder 47)
  - Clippings tipped-in to Schmitz, Anne-Marie. In search of Steinbeck n.d. (Box 5, Folder 48)
  - Articles by and about John Steinbeck 1939 - 1965 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Articles by and about John Steinbeck 1966 - 1970 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Articles by and about John Steinbeck 1971 - 1978 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Articles by and about John Steinbeck 1978 - 1980 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Articles by and about John Steinbeck 1981 - 1990 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Articles by and about John Steinbeck: bound facsimiles of clippings 1939 - 1990 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Seven original dance masks collected by John Steinbeck and formerly housed in his Pacific Grove residence. n.d. (Box 10 - 16)
- Series 11. Steinbeck and Hamilton Family Photographs, 1870s-1981
  - "Our Family": John Adolph and Almira Ann Steinbeck and their children ca. 1870 (Box 8, Othertype 1)
    - 1 photograph: b. & w.; 21 x 26 cm.
  - Steinbeck 50th wedding anniversary: Charles, John Ernst, Mary, Olive, Agnes, Bertha, John, Ella, Esther, May, Willis, Flora, Thelma, Will, Harry, Beth, Eugene, Grace, John Adolph, Willie, Karl, Almira Ann, Richard, Earl, Fred, and Neva posed on the steps of the Hollister house 1906 (Box 8, Othertype 2)
    - 1 photograph: b. & w.; 21 x 16 cm.
  - The Steinbeck men at the 50th wedding anniversary: Harry, Will, John A., Charles, and (John) Ernst standing on the garden path of the Steinbeck home in Hollister, Calif. 1906 (Box 8, Othertype 3)
    - 1 photograph: b. & w.; 8 x 6 cm.
  - Almira Ann Steinbeck standing in the garden of the Steinbeck home in Hollister, Calif. n.d. (Box 8, Othertype 4)
    - 1 photograph: b. & w.; 8 x 1 cm.
  - 50th Wedding anniversary announcement: "Almira Ann Dickson, |Groton, Mass. | John Adolph Steinbeck,| Homberg, Germany. |Fiftieth Wedding Anniversary | Mr. and Mrs. J. A. Steinbeck | Hollister, California, June first, | nineteen hundred and six | Married | Jerusalem, Palestine, | 1856." 1906 (Box 8, Othertype 5)
  - John Adolph Steinbeck standing with a cane in the orchard of the Steinbeck home. 1906 (Box 8, Othertype 6)
    - 1 photograph: b. & w.; 8 x 11 cm.
  - Party tent for the Steinbeck 50th Wedding anniversary 1906 (Box 8, Othertype 7)
    - 1 photograph: b. & w.; 11 x 8 cm.
  - The John Adolph Steinbeck ranch house in Hollister, Calif. n.d. (Box 8, Othertype 8)
    - 1 photograph: b. & w.; 11 x 8 cm.
  - John Adolph and Almira Ann Steinbeck standing in the garden of the Steinbeck home in Hollister, Calif. n.d. (Box 8, Othertype 9)
    - 1 photograph: b. & w.; 11 x 8 cm.
  - Esther, Grace, and Agnes Steinbeck seated on the steps of the Hollister house. 1906 (Box 8, Othertype 10)
    - 1 photograph: b. & w.; 11 x 8 cm.
  - Eight boys seated on the steps of the Hollister house; John Steinbeck, the youngest, is in the middle. n.d. (Box 8, Othertype 11)
    - 1 photograph: b. & w.; 11 x 8 cm.
  - The garden walk and yard of the Steinbeck Hollister home 1906 (Box 8, Othertype 12)
    - 1 photograph: b. & w.; 11 x 8 cm.
  - Almira Ann Steinbeck (top center), Olive Hamilton Steinbeck (right), and four other Steinbeck women seated on the steps of the Hollister house. n.d. (Box 8, Othertype 13)
    - 1 photograph: b. & w.; 11 x 8 cm.
  - Almira Ann Steinbeck seated in a horse-drawn carriage n.d. (Box 8, Othertype 14)
    - 1 photograph: b. & w.; 11 x 8 cm.
  - The Steinbeck granddaughters: Thelma, Grace, Beth, Esther, Agnes, and Mary on the steps of the Steinbeck house in Hollister, Calif. n.d. (Box 8, Othertype 15)
    - 1 photograph: b. & w.; 11 x 8 cm.
  - John Adolph and Almira Ann Steinbeck seated in a horse-drawn carriage n.d. (Box 8, Othertype 16)
    - 1 photograph: b. & w.; 6 x 9 cm.
  - John Ernst Steinbeck with his arm around his mother, Almira Ann Steinbeck, in the garden. n.d. (Box 8, Othertype 17)
    - 1 photograph: b. & w.; 24 x 26 cm.
  - John Adolph Steinbeck standing in the yard n.d. (Box 8, Othertype 18)
    - 1 photograph: b. & w.; 5 x 10 cm.
  - John Adolph Steinbeck standing with a hoe n.d. (Box 8, Othertype 19)
    - 1 photograph: b. & w.; 8 x 11 cm.
  - The Hamilton family home, Ireland n.d. (Box 8, Othertype 20)
    - 1 photograph (facsim.): b. & w.; 9 x 14 cm.
  - Hamilton 50th wedding anniversary: Top left to right: John Ernst Steinbeck, Mamie Hamilton, Will Hamilton, Joe Hamilton, Elizabeth Hamilton Farrell and husband, Dessie Hamilton, Will Martin, Mollie Hamilton Martin. 2nd Row: Olive Hamilton Steinbeck, George Hamilton, Della Hamilton, Eliza Hamilton, Sam Hamilton. 3rd Row: Beth Steinbeck, Marian Hamilton, Esther Steinbeck 1899 (Box 8, Othertype 21)
    - 1 photograph: b. & w.; 21 x 16 cm.
  - Portrait of Elizabeth Fagen Hamilton. Columbian Art Gallery. n.d. (Box 8, Othertype 22)
    - 1 photograph: b. & w.; 11 x 16 cm.
  - Elizabeth Fagen Hamilton n.d. (Box 8, Othertype 23)
    - 1 photograph: b. & w.; 9 x 9 cm.
  - Portrait of Samuel Hamilton n.d. (Box 8, Othertype 24)
    - 1 photograph: b. & w.; 20 x 25 cm.
  - Olive Hamilton (Steinbeck) middle row, second from right. 1883, West End School 1883 (Box 8, Othertype 25)
    - 1 photograph: b. & w.; 18 x 13 cm.
  - Joe Hamilton in his room at Encina Hall, Stanford University. Three men seated at a table, "They studied by a smoky glim until the night was spent," is printed on a sign on the table. n.d. (Box 8, Othertype 26)
    - 1 photograph: b. & w.; 17 x 12 cm.
  - John Ernst Steinbeck, Salinas City, CA: J. Ed. Bacon n.d. (Box 8, Othertype 27)
    - 1 photograph: b. & w.; 11 x 17 cm.
  - Olive Hamilton Steinbeck n.d. (Box 8, Othertype 28)
    - 1 photograph: b. & w.; 10 x 15 cm.
  - John Ernst Steinbeck (middle back row), Olive Hamilton Steinbeck (right end middle row). Nineteen men and women in front of an Order of the Eastern Star backdrop n.d. (Box 8, Othertype 29)
    - 1 photograph: b. & w.; 19 x 15 cm.
  - Mollie Hamilton Martin. Mollie's head is superimposed on an etching of a woman's figure--in the manner of Gibson. By Steckel, L.F. n.d. (Box 8, Othertype 30)
    - 1 photograph: b. & w.; 10 x 13 cm.
  - Dessie Hamilton in a garden n.d. (Box 8, Othertype 31)
    - 1 photograph: b. & w.; 8 x 8 cm.
  - Elizabeth Hamilton Farrell. Signed: "7-XII-07 Greetings E.H.F." 1907 Dec. 7 (Box 8, Othertype 32)
    - 1 photograph: b. & w.; 13 x 9 cm.
  - Olive Hamilton Steinbeck n.d. (Box 8, Othertype 33)
    - 1 photograph: b. & w.; 8 x 8 cm.
  - Mollie Hamilton Martin n.d. (Box 8, Othertype 34)
    - 1 photograph: b. & w.; 8 x 8 cm.
  - Mollie Hamilton Martin n.d. (Box 8, Othertype 35)
    - 1 photograph: b. & w.; 8 x 8 cm.
  - Olive Hamilton Steinbeck seated in the front of a biplane n.d. (Box 8, Othertype 36)
    - 1 photograph: b. & w.; 14 x 9 cm.
  - Horse-drawn wagon filled with fourteen children, John Ernst Steinbeck at the reins n.d. (Box 8, Othertype 37)
    - 1 photograph: b. & w.; 21 x 16 cm.
  - W. J. Martin, Mollie Hamilton Martin, Genevieve Smith, David R. Davies. Written on verso: "Where the wolf and the plaintive jackal howl for their prey at the evening fall." Yosemite Valley, June 26, 1901. 1901 June 26 (Box 8, Othertype 38)
    - 1 photograph: b. & w.; 17 x 12 cm.
  - The John Ernst Steinbeck home, Salinas, Calif. n.d. (Box 8, Othertype 39)
    - 1 photograph: b. & w.; 15 x 10 cm.
  - O[live] E[sther] S[teinbeck] at nine months. Hollister, CA: J. M. Pickett, Photo. 1893 (Box 8, Othertype 40)
    - 1 photograph: b. & w.; 11 x 17 cm.
  - O[live] E[sther] S[teinbeck] 8 months in white christening gown. Hollister, CA: J. M. Pickett, Photo. 1893 (Box 8, Othertype 41)
    - 1 photograph: b. & w.; 11 x 17 cm.
  - Beth Steinbeck seated on a table in a white dress. Elite studio, Jones and Lotz, 838 Market St., San Francisco, Calif. n.d. (Box 8, Othertype 42)
    - 1 photograph: b. & w.; 11 x 17 cm.
  - Beth, John, and Esther Steinbeck 1904 (Box 8, Othertype 43)
    - 1 photograph: b. & w.; 10 x 14 cm.
  - Beth, John, and Esther Steinbeck 1904 (Box 8, Othertype 44)
    - 1 photograph: b. & w.; 10 x 14 cm.
  - Beth, John, and Esther Steinbeck 1904 (Box 8, Othertype 45)
    - 1 photograph: b. & w.; 10 x 14 cm.
  - Esther, John, and Beth Steinbeck 1904 (Box 8, Othertype 46)
    - 1 photograph: b. & w.; 10 x 14 cm.
  - Esther, John, and Beth Steinbeck 1904 (Box 8, Othertype 47)
    - 1 photograph: b. & w.; 10 x 14 cm.
  - Esther, John, and Beth Steinbeck 1904 (Box 8, Othertype 48)
    - 1 photograph: b. & w.; 10 x 14 cm.
  - Esther Steinbeck, age 3. n.d. (Box 8, Othertype 49)
    - 1 photograph: b. & w.; 10 x 10 cm.
  - Esther Steinbeck, age 3. n.d. (Box 8, Othertype 50)
    - 1 photograph: b. & w.; 10 x 10 cm.
  - Esther Steinbeck. Salinas, CA: Butler studio n.d. (Box 8, Othertype 51)
    - 1 photograph: b. & w.; 8 x 17 cm.
  - Esther Steinbeck. Salinas, CA: Butler studio n.d. (Box 8, Othertype 52)
    - 1 photograph: b. & w.; 8 x 17 cm.
  - Seven children holding flags next to a building. Written on verso: "'The Raw Recruits,' 'The first home guard of Paso Robles,' Esther and Beth [Steinbeck] are the ends. To Grandma from Esther and Beth." n.d. (Box 8, Othertype 53)
    - 1 photograph: b. & w.; 19 x 9 cm.